[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
creation of tosca api test cases data
parameterization verification and
execution of tosca api test cases
the explanation will be done through
hands-on demonstration
all right
let's start with the api test case
creation
two options are available to create the
api test cases
[Music]
first we can choose the export to api
test case option to create modules and
basic test cases from the api scan
wizard
[Music]
the second approach is to create the
test cases using the modules which are
created during the export
[Music]
now i will guide you to create the test
cases by opting the export api test case
option
select the root folder and click on
export option under api test case option
to generate test cases and modules
oops this error appeared as i forgot to
check out the tosca workspace
let me please check out the project
folder first and do the same step again
[Music]
once the process done close the api scan
wizard
now we can see that modules and test
cases sections are created in new
component folder with the name api scan
underscore import
[Music]
the modules section contains all the
modules which are created during the
scanning the modules are available
within the respective functionality wise
created folders
for each of api two modules are created
one for request and another for response
we can use these modules later to create
the test cases
[Music]
now let's see the test case section
which contains the basic test cases for
each of the apis which are scanned
previously
each of the test case has two steps
one for sending the request and another
for receiving the responses
[Music]
this are the default test cases which
are generated based on structured in api
scan wizard
[Music]
now i will guide you to create the test
cases with the help of api modules which
are created during the export
this is similar approach to create tosca
test cases for any ui application
here we will perform a sample test
scenarios for swagger application
the steps are 1 authenticate using valid
user credential 2 add coffee item free
search and verify the new coffee item
let's start the demonstration now
as per the test scenario we will use
request and response modules related to
authentication and copies
the input data of default api to modules
are hard coded
so first we need to create the modules
attributes to make it parameterized
we will click on buffer module
attributes with dynamic list items
option to open attribute assistant
select password and username attributes
and click on add to create attributes
two module attributes are created for
username and password
similarly we will create attributes for
post post login data response module for
the response field status code and token
next we will create the attributes for
module post pst coffee request
the attributes need to be created for
name description and authorization field
from the attribute assistant screen we
will select the corresponding fields and
click on add
[Music]
we need to create attributes for post
post coffee response module for the
response field status code and id of
newly created coffee item
the other respond fields are not
required
[Music]
next we need to create attributes for
modules to find a coffee using the
coffee
[Music]
here we will create attributes for the
authorization and id field for the get
gt coffee by id request module
finally we we will now create attributes
for get gt coffee by id response module
for the response field status code and
name
this name attribute will be used for
verification
all the required modules are now
parameterized
host post login data request has two
required attributes post post login data
response has attributes
similarly the attributes are also
created for other required modules
all right we will now create the test
case using these modules
we will first navigate to test cases
section and create a new test case with
name add coffee
[Music]
next we will create trees test step
folders with the name authentication
[Music]
post coffee
and verify new coffee
next we need to pull the required
modules
first we will drag and drop login data
request and response modules to the test
step folder authentication
[Music]
next we will drag and drop post coffee
request and response modules to the test
step folder post coffee
[Music]
finally we will drag and drop gt coffee
by id request and response modules to
the test step folder verify new coffee
[Music]
we need to update the test step with
data and action
in post login data request step we will
provide the valid password and username
to generate the session authorization
token
this token will be used to perform any
transactions such as add coffee or
search by coffee id
for post login data response step we
verify the success code
0 ok for status code attribute to check
the authentication
then we will store the token number in
auth token buffer that will be used
later
[Music]
now we will enter the new coffee details
to the step post cough request
enter name as test 1
[Music]
enter the value of description attribute
as test coffee
enter value of authorization attribute
as token space off token buffer
[Music]
now we will check if the coffee
successfully created or not
[Music]
so we need to perform verification
against the status code attribute for
post coffee response step
and store the value of id in a buffer
next step is to find the newly created
coffee
to perform this we will update the id
attribute of the gt coffee by id request
step with the id buffer which holds the
id of newly created coffee item
also the authorization attribute has to
be updated accordingly
now we have to perform the final
verification in step get coffee by id
response
first perform verification for status
code attribute with success code 200 ok
after that we will verify the name which
was provided during the coffee creation
[Music]
the api test case is created and ready
for execution
it looks like this
[Music]
this test case can be executed through
the scratch book by selecting run in
scratchbook option
here we will execute it through the
execution list first check out the
execution section
[Music]
create execution list folder with name
api suite
[Music]
and create an execution list with name
swagger app
[Music]
dot we will drag and drop the newly
created api test case ad copy into the
execution list swagger app
now execute this execution list by
selecting the run option after right
clicking on it
it will take few seconds to complete the
execution
no ui will be appeared during execution
as it will be done through api interface
we can now view the execution logs to
check the status of all api transactions
all the buffer are created successfully
[Music]
also we can view the final verification
of coffee creation has been done
successfully
the buffers which are created during the
execution can be seen from buffer viewer
section
[Music]
save and check in the workspace to store
the test case in repository
[Music]
thanks for watching this video
that's all about api scanning using
tosca
we will learn more about api test
automation approach in next video
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain you can check our other
website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query